Sam Clark

Sam.clark48@hotmail.co.uk | +44 7981 339 346

LinkedIn | GitHub | Portfolio

Sutton, Greater London

Profile

Self-motivated, organised software engineering graduate with experience developing frontend and back-end solutions using Java, Kotlin, TypeScript, React and more. Made use of software development skills to develop high quality, maintainable personal projects utilising proper design patterns, object-oriented fundamentals and proper project planning.

Education

Software Engineering BEng Honours

Sep 2021 – Jun 2024

University of Westminster – First Class Honours

- Developed several projects using Java, Kotlin, Swift, React.js & more.
- Achieved consistently high results across modules
- Student Member of the British Computing Society (BCS)

OCR Level 3 Cambridge Technical Diploma in IT

Sep 2017 – Jun 2019

Carshalton College – Distinction* Distinction*

GCSE Sep 2015 – Jun 2017

Sutton College

• Mathematics at Grade C | English at Grade 5

Employment

Retail Assistant

Jul 2024 – Present

Primark, Kingston Upon Thames & Sutton

Apr 2022 – Oct 2022

- Provided customers with great service on both the shop floor and on tills.
- Ensured that sections of the shop floor were tidy and maintained across the shift.
- Handled sorting of customer returns and redistribution onto the shop floor

Technical Skills

Programming Languages: Java, Kotlin, TypeScript, JavaScript, C#, Swift, HTML, CSS, PHP, SQL

Frameworks: React, Next.js, Sass, Bootstrap, Spring Boot, Electron.js

Databases: MySQL, SQLite, MariaDB, Firebase, Google Firestore

 $\textbf{Other:} \ \operatorname{Model-View-ViewModel} \ (\operatorname{MVVM}), \ \operatorname{Controller-Service-Repository} \ (\operatorname{CSR}), \ \operatorname{REST} \ \operatorname{APIs}, \ \operatorname{CI/CD}, \ \operatorname{CI/$

Git, GitHub, Pair Programming, KanbanFlow, Trello.

Projects

L2J Database Website & Server Web API

Collaborative Project

Java Spring Boot & MariaDB (Back-end) | TypeScript, Next.js & Bootstrap (Front-end)

- Co-development of an API based on data from a game server, with appropriate endpoints.
- Retrieves and parses game data from MariaDB relational database, XML and TSV files.
- Uses a Controller-Service-Repository pattern to ensure separation of concerns.
- Database website utilises API endpoints to populate pages with appropriate data, including search and filtering.
- Experience submitting pull requests with conventional commits structure.
- Gained experience participating in pair-programming sessions.

Web Scraper & Discord Bot

Personal Project

Java, MySQL & Discord4J

- Designed custom web scraper application retrieves most recent news feed posts by parsing website HTML data using Jsoup and Playwright
- Discord bot application utilises the web scraper application along with Discord4J and MySQL
- Bot stores post data from previously retrieved posts and periodically checks for new posts through web scraper functionality, embedding new posts onto specified discord channels.
- Utilised reactive programming techniques through Discord4J.

Just the News

Personal Project

Kotlin & Firebase

- Developed an Android-based news application using Kotlin & Firebase.
- Provided clear UI/UX design through use of DrawerLayout, RecyclerView & more.
- Implemented location services to retrieve news based on the user's location if the country is supported by the News API service, as well as option to manually set country.
- Utilised Firebase to store user account data upon account creation and for authentication when logging in, as well as other persistent data needs such as the user setting their location.
- Included support for Google Login functionality.

Digital eCommerce Games Media Application

Final Year Project

TypeScript, React.js, CSS, Node.js, Electron & SQLite

- Developed a digital eCommerce application using React.js & Electron framework.
- Utilised IGDB API service to retrieve game product data in JSON format.
- Included an account system with functionality to login, add products to basket and checkout, see recently viewed products and more.
- Ability for user to search by name or genre, as well as see new or upcoming releases.
- Library section for user to view products that they purchased (no payment processing included) and filter by genre and sort alphabetically.

References

References available upon request.